准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
文化冲击
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
免费沙拉台
不收费
来跳舞
免费沙拉台
不收费
免费
我就不明白了
I just don't get it
连免费沙拉台都招呼不到客人的话
If a free salad bar doesn't bring in customers
还有啥能招
what will?
章鱼哥
Squidward
什么事
Yes, sir?
这里需要有一些变动
There's going to be some changes around here
零 钱
有客人
A customer
欢迎光临蟹堡王
Welcome to the Krusty Krab
海绵宝宝  无微不至关照他
SpongeBob, cater to his every whim
这回可别搞砸了
and don't screw this one up
遵命老板
Aye, aye, sir
欢迎登船  先生
Welcome aboard, sir
在蟹堡王这里  您就是船长
Here at the Krusty Krab, you are the Captain
而我是您船上的佣人
and I am your cabin boy
倘若您颇有微词
You just say the word
我就自觉去关禁闭
and I will throw myself in the brig
能为您点餐了吗
May I take your order?
我只想换零钱打公用电话
All I wanted was change for the pay phone
遵命  先生
Aye, aye, sir
先生的零钱
"Monsieur's changez"
谢谢
Thanks
给你吧
Here you go
好啊
Yeah
你们可能也注意到了
As you may have noticed
本月利润严重下滑
profits are way down this month
需要来个营销噱头吸引顾客
We need a gimmick to bring in customers
你们两个旱鸭子有什么办法吗
Do you lubbers have any ideas?
我有一个
l've got one
每笔消费附赠一双免费袜子
a free pair of socks with every purchase
或许可以来  午夜双堡疯
Or maybe Double-Patty Midnight Madness
有了
I know
满嘴蛤蜊日行不行
How about Mouthful of Clams Day?
谁要是满嘴塞着蛤蜊过来
Everyone who shows up with a mouthful of clams
就能领取免费饮料
gets a free drink
那个
Well, uh
我考虑的是现场表演之类的事
I was thinking more
along the lines of live entertainment
就是这个
That's it
现场表演
a floor show
不对  等下
No, wait
是才艺表演
a talent show
主持人就是
with your host
我
me
这个时刻是我
This is the moment I've
我是说我们  一直梦寐以求的
I mean, we've been dreaming of
想想看  蟹老板
Think of it, Mr. Krabs
你可以把文化
you will be responsible for bringing culture
带到所谓裤头村的这片文化沙漠里
into this cultural wasteland we call Bikini Bottom
更不用说钱了
And not to mention the money
钱
The money?
我现在就可以预见到
And I can see it now
你女儿珍珍
Your daughter, Pearl
会变得名声响亮
Her name up in lights
小珍珍
Little Pearlie
明星
a star?
天啊
Hopping clams
才艺表演
A talent show
我特有才艺
I'm talented
得打电话叫爸妈来
I'd better call the folks
章鱼哥  就这么定了
Squidward, you've got a deal
让我家闺女变成明星
Make my little girl a star
章鱼哥  我要什么时候上台
Hey, Squidward, what time am I going on?
上什么
Going on what?
上台表演啊
The show
我什么时候要上台表演
When am I going on the show?
我有样很厉害的表演
I have a great act
敢问你有什么才艺
What talent could you possibly possess?
哒哒
Ta-dah
连你爸妈都不会想看那玩意的
No one, not even your parents would want to see that
大家想看的是文化
What the people want is culture
不是会跳舞的泡泡
not dancing bubbles
我明白
Okay, I get it
放心好了  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我要构思出史上最有文化的表演
l'm going to come up with the most cultured act ever
我都等不及了
I can hardly wait
那家伙唯一有文化的地方就是网球鞋
The only culture that guy has is in his tennis shoes
培养真菌
网球鞋
Tennis shoes
笑死我了
I crack myself up
我们现在在蟹堡王才艺表演的现场
We are live at the Krusty Krab talent show
为大家呈现顶尖的才艺
featuring the finest talent
座无虚席
A full house
爸妈来了
There's Mom and Dad
他们会特骄傲的
They are going to be so proud
你们好  我是蟹老板
Hello, I'm Mr. Krabs
我喜欢钱
and I like money
我得准备好
I got to get ready
大家都听好了
All right, listen up, people, listen up
大家都靠过来
Gather around, everyone
赶紧
Chop chop
你们可能会觉得
Now, you may be thinking
这是你们大红大紫的唯一机会
this is your one shot at the big time
想得美
Well, it's not
这机会是我的
It's mine
章鱼哥  表演这个怎么样
Hey, Squid, how about this for the show?
吸水先生
神奇的吸水先生
The amazing Mr. Absorbency
哒哒
Ta-dah
没人想看你吸水膨胀
No one is going to want to see you engorge yourself
求你了  章鱼哥
Please, Squidward
让我上台表演吧
let me be in the show
我会做任何事的
I'll do anything
任何事  任何事
anything, anything
所以说你真的要参加表演吗
So, you really want to be in the show?
真的
Yes
行  表演完了你就去拖地
Okay, you get to mop up afterwards
能不能别来烦我了
Now, will you stop bugging me?
原来这种感受就是
So, this is what it feels like
大红大紫
the big time
有了这个拖把  我就能重塑我的命运
With this mop, I shape my destiny
晚上好  欢欢迎观赏
Good evening, and-and welcome
第一届一年一度章鱼哥才艺表演
to the first annual Squidward Tentacles talent show
本表演赞助者为蟹堡王
sponsored by the Krusty Krab
蟹黄堡之家
home of the Krabby Patty
因为不会有别人会给这玩意一个家
because no one else would give it a home
谢谢
Thank you
接下来的表演
Our next act
充分证明了走后门现象依然猖獗
is living proof that nepotism is alive and well
走后
Nepoti
谢谢
Thank you
各位鳍声有请
Put your fins together for
各位
Put your
各
Put
珍珍
Pearl
万岁
Hooray
我的闺女终于变成明星了
My little girl is finally a star
给我一个蟹
Give me a K-r-u
给我一个堡
Give me a s-t-y
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
这才叫做才艺嘛
Now, that's what I call talent
谢谢
Thank you
我的腿
My legs
谢谢
Thank you
章鱼哥  我跟你说
Hey, Squidward, listen
你说要怎样
what do you think?
我拖地应不应该前后拖
When I mop, should I go forward and back?
不对  等下
No, no, wait
从左到右
side to side
接下来是诗歌朗诵
And now, poetry
朗诵者
by
小蜗
Gary
他真是字字珠玑
He has such a way with words
快啊快啊  大诗人
Come on, come on, Ginsberg
再不赶紧念完
If he doesn't hurry it up
就没时间上演压轴好戏了
we're not going to have enough time for the best act
我的好戏
me
章鱼哥  该用清洁先生还是干净博士
Squidward, should I use Mr. Cleanser or Dr. Clean?
都行
Yes
神奇浮游生物
我  神奇浮游生物
I, The Amazing Plankton
要用这套魔术戏法
with the use of prestidigitation
在你们眼皮底下让一个蟹黄堡消失
will make a Krabby Patty disappear
before your very eyes
首先  我需要一位观众自愿配合
First, I'll need a volunteer from the audience
你想得美
Nice try
你演完了  小东西
Your act's over, bub
这次姑且让你赢一回
You may win this time
瞬间转移
Shee-ah kazing
倒霉透了
Well, this stinks
下去
Get out
赶紧下台
Get off the stage
章鱼哥
Squidward
这场表演烂透了
This show is a disaster
你这是要毁了我
You're ruining me
好啦蟹老板  放心
Now, now, don't you worry, Mr. Krabs
我特别留了最佳节目做压轴
l've saved the best for last
瞧好了
you'll see
看在你份上  希望你没说错
For your sake, I hope you're right
现在  女士们先生们
And now, ladies and gentlemen
你们期盼的时刻终于到来了
the moment you've all been waiting for
我们留了最好的节目压轴
We've saved the best for last
各位掌声有请无与伦比章鱼哥
Put your hands together for
the incomparable Squidward
章鱼哥秀
搞什么
What the?
免费沙拉台
不收费
这样下去我会亏钱的
I'm losing money on this deal
每分钱都值得花
It's worth every penny
你们这些臭鱼烂虾
You bottom feeders
完全不懂才艺
You don't even know talent
不要才艺
No talent
章鱼哥  我现在能上台了吗
Hey, Squidward, can I go on now?
行  演完了
Yeah, show's over
不错
Yeah
这还真的不错
That's really not too bad
我喜欢
I like that
不错嘛
All right
我们还要
We want more
他们要我返场
They want an encore
站一边去  海绵宝宝
Stand aside, SpongeBob
我们还
We want
我们还要
We want more
你成功了  章鱼哥
You did it, Squidward
这场表演真棒
What a great show
我儿子是明星了
My son's a star
谁知道他竟然有这般才艺
Who ever knew he had such talent?
我需要再来一辆手推车
I'll be needing another wheelbarrow
准备下周的表演
for next week's show
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
啊
Ah
蟹堡王的午餐时间
lunchtime at The Krusty Krab
大家都在享用着蟹黄堡
everyone enjoying their Krabby Patties
这是怎么了
What's this?
找得到吗  章鱼哥先生
Can you spot her, Mr. Squidward?
在那里  老板
Down there, sir
看来发生了一场蟹黄堡绑架案
There appears to be a Krabby Patty-napping in progress
凶手只有一个
There can be only one culprit
蟹堡王
痞老板
Plankton
胜利总算是我的了
Finally, victory is mine
我赢了  我赢了
I win, I win
我赢了
I win
他逃走了  老板
He got away, sir
不要
No
他最终还是偷走了我的秘密配方
He's finally stolen me secret recipe
那可未必  蟹老板
Perhaps not, Monsieur Krabs
因为还有
for it's
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
差不多得了
Okay, that's far enough
真该死
Tartar sauce
魔术店
你有没有看到个蟹黄堡
Have you seen a Krabby Patty?
差不多有这么高
It's about this tall, and
魔术店
是魔术店
A magic shop
你是魔术师吗
Are you a magician?
有一次  我见到这么个魔术师
One time I saw this magician
他做了这个  然后
and he did this thing, a-and he
总之他就跟咱说
Anyway, and then he told us
如果你相信自己
"if you believe in yourself
只要有一小撮魔力
"and with a tiny pinch of magic
你所有梦想都会成真的
all your dreams can come true"
我受不了了
I can't take it
痞老板  是你
Plankton, it's you
没错  这些年来
Yes, and after all these years
我以为我就是折磨大师
l thought I was the master of torture
可那样
But that
那样太没理了
that just wasn't fair
给
Here
拿走这个破蟹黄堡
Take the stupid patty
反正我也不要秘密配方了
l don't want the secret recipe anyway
估计我餐厅不会有蟹堡王那么成功了
I guess my restaurant
will never be as good as the Krusty Krab
海之霸
你就是不知道当废物是个什么样子
You don't know what it's like to be a loser
振作起来  痞老板
Cheer up, Plankton
我觉得你是赢家
I think you're a winner
你
What
你说什么
what did you say?
我说你是个
I said you're a
废物
Loser
当裤头村公敌感觉怎么样啊  痞老板
How does it feel to be the most hated thing
in Bikini Bottom, Plankton?
是不是很难受
It hurts, doesn't it?
我知道
I know
是啊  为了庆祝成功赶走你
Yeah, and for running you out
我们要给这个小朋友
we're going to make this kid
授予今日裤头村荣誉好小子称号
honorary town rookie of the day
因为他是一个好小子
For he's a jolly good rookie
[ 改自歌曲"For He's a Jolly Good Fellow" ]
因为他是一个好小子
For he's a jolly good rookie
他只要有一个朋友的话
I bet if he had just one friend
就肯定不会这么坏了
he wouldn't be such a meanie
子
ie
没有人会否认这
Which nobody
随便了
Whatever
海之霸
有客人
A customer?
我们今天的特餐是海霸
Our special today is chum
什锦饭
balaya
嗨  痞老板
Hi, Mr. Plankton
你今天害我丢脸丢得还不够大发吗
Haven't you degraded me enough for one day?
对
No
我是说
I mean
我想要你出来跟我玩一玩
l want you to come out and play with me
什么
Wha?
跟
Play
我
with
玩
me
你会引起热核反应吗
You know how to induce thermonuclear fusion?
不知道  可我喜欢跟
No, but I like to go
那个幼稚方块
That naive cube
我还得受多长时间的罪
How long must I suffer this?
你是不是没有让他走开
You're not letting him leave, are you?
看不出来吗
Can't you see?
这可是复仇的大好时机
This is the perfect opportunity for revenge
说详细点
Elaborate
跟海绵宝宝交朋友
Befriend the SpongeBob
然后等到时机刚刚好  就带走蟹黄堡
Then, when the time is just right, take the Krabby Patty
带走
Take
蟹黄堡
the Krabby Patty
快去  小天才
Get moving, genius
可别让他走了
don't let him get away
朋友到水母田里捉水母
fishing with my friends in Jellyfish Fields
海绵宝宝  我会玩你的小游戏的
All right, SpongeBob, I'll play your little game
好棒
Right
最后一个到水母田的是臭蛤蜊
Last one to the fields is a rotten clam
那么  我来拿大网
So, I get the big net
你来拿小网
and you get the little net
吃了水母会怎么样
What happens after we eat them?
不是吃水母  要这样捉水母
You don't eat them, you catch them, like this
就那样
Like that
然后呢
And?
然后就把水母放了
Then you throw them back
不过要小心触手
but watch out for stingers
触手
Stingers?
全天下都得向痞老板下跪
All knees will bow to Plankton
痞老板万岁
Hail, Plankton
我赢了  我赢了
I win, I win
重点不在于输赢  在于快乐
It's not about winning, it's about fun
那是啥东西
What's that?
快乐就是你在
Fun is when you
快乐就是
Fun is
就像
It's like
是一种
It's kind of
有点像是
Sort of like a
快乐是什么
What is fun?
我来给你拼一下
Let me spell it for you
F表示朋友  一起同甘共苦
"F" is for friends who do stuff together
U表示你和我
"U" is for you and me
N表示无论何时无论何地
"N" is for anywhere and anytime at all
在这蓝蓝深海里
Down here in the deep blue sea
快乐
F表示放火  烧掉整座镇子
"F" is fire that burns down the whole town
U表示原子
"U" is for uranium
弹
bombs
N表示无人生还  到时你
"N" is for no survivors when you
痞老板  这些可不是快乐的内涵所在
Plankton, those things aren't what fun is all about
现在这么做
Now, do it like this
F表示朋友  一起同甘
"F" is for friends who
不要
Never
完全白痴得要死
That's completely idiotic
来  我帮你
Here, let me help you
F表示朋友  一起同甘共苦
"F" is for friends who do stuff together
U表示你和我
"U" is for you and me
试试看
Try it
N表示无论何时无论何地
"N" is for anywhere and anytime at all
在这蓝蓝深海里
Down here in the deep blue sea
等等  我不太明白
Wait, I don't understand this
我觉得我内心麻麻的
I feel all tingly inside
该停下来了吗
Should we stop?
不该停  你有这种感觉才对呢
No, that's how you're supposed to feel
我喜欢
Well, I like it
那就再来一遍
Let's do it again
好
Okay
F表示嬉戏  在这花田里
"F" is for frolic through all the flowers
U表示尤克里里
"U" is for ukulele
N表示挑鼻子
"N" is for nose picking
分泡泡糖  舔沙子
sharing gum and sand licking
跟我好兄弟一起
Here with my best buddy
快乐
叛变了
Mutiny
海之霸
之后呢
And after that
我们就在花田里嬉戏  然后
we frolicked through the flowers and then we
听起来很快乐
Sounds like fun
最快乐的那部分是我们
Well, the really fun part was when we
偷蟹黄堡的事情你都干了多少
What did you do with the Krabby Patty?
什么
The what?
蟹黄堡  忘了吗
The Krabby Patty, remember?
这事是急不得的  懂不
You can't rush these things, you know
你都把任务忘了
You're forgetting the mission
秘方
你这是说什么
What are you talking about?
你都要被同化了  痞老板
You're going native, Plankton
看看你自己
Look at yourself
干嘛
What?
我有好些时候没看到痞老板了
I haven't seen Plankton for a while
他肯定是在密谋什么
He must be scheming
谁知道
Who knows?
多半洗心革面了吧
Maybe he's changed
谁知道
Who knows?
我看你知道
I think you knows
快乐
都说他洗心革面了
He's changed, I tell you
海绵兄弟
Sponge buddy?
痞老板兄弟  走吧
Plankton buddy, let's go
我都忘了这里是禁友区
I forgot this is a no-friends zone
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
能不能借一步说话
may I speak to you in private?
你不介意我把这玩意放这吧
You won't mind if I set this here, will you?
你这是要干嘛  蟹老板
What's this all about, Mr. Krabs?
他是个贼
He's a thief
你看他眼里的欲望  他要
look at the lust in his eye, he's
你咋就不能接受我们的友情
Why can't you just accept our friendship?
他目的是我秘方
He's just after me recipe
我会给你证明的
I'll prove it to you
你大老远走过来一定是饿了吧
You must be hungry after that long walk over here
没错  不过我要留点胃口
Yes, but I'm saving my appetite
去电影院吃爆米花
for some popcorn at the movies
随你便
Suit yourself
我们受够你那些小测试了  蟹老板
We've had enough of your little tests, Mr. Krabs
痞老板  我们出去吧
Come on, Plankton, let's get out of here
也许那小子说得对
Maybe the lad was right
也许痞老板改过自新了
Maybe Plankton's gone straight
也许太阳要打西边出来了
And maybe scallops will fly out of my pants
坚持住  小子
Hang on there, laddie
我来了
l'm a-comin'
我好喜欢续集  痞老板
I sure like sequels, Plankton
海霸王  你坐到我朋友身上了
Hey, bubble bass, you're sitting on my friend
海霸王
Hey, bubble bass
谢谢你  朋友
Thanks for that, friend
那是当然
Sure thing
听好
Listen up
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs?
他这是在骗你
He's deceiving you
把手伸进他口袋  拿出里面的东西
Reach into his pocket now, and take what he's got
你也一样  小子
You, too, boy
我真不敢相信
I can't believe this
不是你想的那样
It's not what you think
那这是什么
What is it, then?
快说你眼前这是什么
Tell me what you see here
我
I
我什么都没看见
I don't see anything
你怎么会没看见
How can you not see it?
好好好  我看见了
Okay, okay, I see it
不就是个蟹黄堡吗
It's a Krabby Patty, okay?
我就是忍不住
I couldn't help it
可我们明明唱了快乐歌
But we sang the fun song
我觉得我要吐了
I think I'm going to be sick
多久了
How long?
久什么
How long what?
你密谋做这事多久了
How long were you planning on doing this?
跟我说
Tell me
什么
What?
好吧  是真的
All right, it's true
我是骗了你才把蟹黄堡弄到手的
l tricked you to get the Krabby Patty
可你却向我示出了友情
But then you showed me friendship
现在我意识到
and now I realize
那才是我真正想要的
that's all I ever really wanted
真的吗
Really?
才怪  假的
No, not really
当恶人可快乐了
Being evil is too much fun
亲爱的  这世间一切都无法拆散我们
Darling, I knew nothing would ever tear us apart
蟹老板  他走了
Mr. Krabs, he's gone
他偷到了蟹黄堡
He got the patty
他赢了
He won
才没有  小子
No, he didn't, boy
知道银幕后边是什么不
Don't you know what's behind these screens?
实心混凝土
Solid concrete
对不起  蟹老板
I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs
我还以为痞老板洗心革面了
I thought Plankton had changed
别怪他  小子
Don't blame him, lad
一切友谊都遭不住蟹黄堡的诱惑
No friendship can withstand
the allure of a Krabby Patty
现在回蟹堡王去
Now, let's go back to the Krusty Krab
来份新鲜蟹黄堡  我请客
and have a fresh one, on me
好的  蟹老板
Aye, aye, Mr. Krabs
还是只打个折算了
Well, maybe at a discount